Elijah Townsend



info@established1992.com



(828)773-9730



http://established1992.com

Summary

A passionate designer who can code, with a strong desire to learn and create. With over 9 years of professional experience in user experience, visual design and front-end development. As a designer who can code, I help bridge the gap between designers and developers.

Experience



Senior Experience Designer

Truist

Dec 2020 - Present (5 months +)

- Creating highly usable solutions for web based applications through business requirements, user research, established patterns, design system components and accessibility standards
- · Strong work ethic with an inherent sense of ownership and responsibility
- Rapidly produce concepts and prototypes; distinguishing between when to build a prototype or create a hi-fidelity mockup
- Collaborate with designers from different platforms to develop a holistic design for clients

Designer, Consultant

Established 1992

Jan 2012 - Present (9 years 4 months +)

- Researched, developed and launched developer resources for Zurb's Foundation Framework, identifying changes between version 5 and version 6, foundation.established1992.com
- · Creating responsive user interfaces that engage customers across different devices and resolutions
- Establishing user-centered designs by creating user-flows and mockups to present to product owner
- Testing cross browser functionality along with optimizing websites for performance

Senior User Interface Designer

Truist

Dec 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 1 month)

- · Building stable and maintainable codebases using Angular
- Performing bug fixes and code review while maintaining an organized workflow using GitLab
- Ensuring proper documentation through all stages of product life cycles
- Implementing company design system into multiple business focus projects
- · Creating and pushing reusable components back into design system for entire company to use



BRAT Senior User Interface Designer

BB&T

Jun 2018 - Dec 2019 (1 year 7 months)

- Creating user-centered designs for our enterprise platform, U, with careful consideration for business requirements, user feedback, and usability findings
- Updating U Web with JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Aria attributes to improve accessibility for all users

and responsive web design.

- Familiarity of World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) guidelines.
- Significant experience with GIT and SVN versioning management.
- Prototyping in Handlebars to show functionality to team.



🕥 UI/UX Designer

Old Dominion Freight Line

Apr 2013 - Jun 2018 (5 years 3 months)

- Implemented the UX & UI strategy to transition AS400 applications over to Java applications with a uniform look and feel
- · Responsible for designing odfl.com through wireframes, mockups, style guides, and front-end frameworks, with over 30,000 daily users
- Responsible for defining style guide, pattern library and coding standards for internal enterprise applications
- · Working in both Agile and Waterfall software development principles
- Meeting with product owners and users to create low/high fidelity mockups and gain usability testing statistics
- Ability to create clickable and functional prototypes through Sketch, Invision or using front-end languages (HTML/CSS/JavaScript)
- Designed a user testing plan utilizing pre-release and post-release user observation tests



UX Product Design Consultant

Civvis

Nov 2016 - Nov 2017 (1 year 1 month)

- Conveyed design concepts and deliverables to business partners through in-person and remote presentations as well as through detailed and easily understood documentation.
- Designing, wireframing and prototyping complex, interactive solutions in a very complex solution space
- · Work with clients to translate business problems and requirements into compelling UI's that demonstrate the power and value of rich internet experiences.



Web Designer

Market Connection - Las Vegas SEO Company

May 2012 - Dec 2012 (8 months)

- Ensuring brand guidelines are adhered to each project
- Collaborating with team members to create layouts and engaging designs
- Updating stylesheets and front-end code as needed

Education



Caldwell Community College and Technical Institute

Associates, Web Technologies

2012 - 2014

Skills

Web Design • Web Development • User Interface Design • Graphic Design • User Experience Design • Interaction Design • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Front-end Development • Angular • HTML

Honors & Awards



2019 Design or Die Challenge Champion

Dec 2019

While working at BB&T, all of the designers had a design competition to showcase each designers skills. The competition was set up in a bracket format to put designers head-to-head. It was tough competition but found myself in the championship. For the championship, we had to create designs and present them to a new team to sell them on our designs. In the end, I won by a slim margin but am grateful for the opportunity to compete against my fellow designers and receive the championship belt!